Guide to the Kathe Burkhart Papers MSS.467
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI. Personal, 1969-2013; 7.75 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder.; 135.1 Megabytes in 185 computer files.; 5 audiocassettes; 1 videocassettes (vhs)
  - Burkhart and Jozef van Wissem Wedding and Performance Piece -- Photographs and Clipping, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Lists -- Burkhart Ephemera and Books, 1996-2012; cuid36260 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_75)
  - Astrological Chart Readings, 1998-2014; cuid36261 (Box 38, Folder 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_70)
  - Images -- Burkhart Portraits, Events, Friends, and Pets, 2007-2014; cuid36262 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_73)
  - Income Spreadsheet, Deductions, Receipt Lists, 2009, 2011; cuid36263 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_74)
  - Images -- Amsterdam Street Festival and Jamaica Trip, 2011-2014; cuid36264 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_72)
  - Burkhart-Designed Party Invitation and Holiday Card, undated (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
  - Notes and Notebook, undated (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
  - Monique Safford Hand colored Prints, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Book Recommendation List from Artist John Baldessari, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten Collage and Images, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Section of White Paper Containing Messages and Signatures, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - "Fabulous Animal and Country Songs", undated (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0003)
  - "Dear Diane / Dear Signora Diane", undated (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0012)
- Series VII. Grace Knipe Papers, 1908-1996; 2.25 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes, and one 1/2 manuscript box.
  The Grace Knipe Papers were accumulated by her niece Kathe Burkhart and include Knipe's personal correspondence, diaries, notebooks, writings, and childhood ephemera, dating from the early 1900s to the 1990s. There is a small amount of early childhood ephemera including early 1900s school notes, as well as early poems and stories written sporadically from 1914 to 1977. Knipe's personal diaries date from 1929 to 1948 and are entered mostly in mini monthly journal books which typically contain daily appointments, family activities, work, national news, and the weather. This series also includes books and notes kept while Knipe participated in a Christian women's group through her church. This series contains a photograph of Knipe at 100 years old and obituaries for her husband William in 1959, and herself in 1996. There is also correspondence from neice Kathe Burkhart and also Knipe's sister dating from the 1970s to the 1980s. Burkhart wrote a book, Between the Lines (published in 2006), which was inspired by letters found after her aunt's death that were from Kate Gibson during the 1920s and 1930s. They appeared to have a close friendship and the letters often included family and friend news as well as events in their daily lives, while Grace worked outside the home in an office, and Kate lived in her family home and dealt with chronic illness.
  - Early Childhood Notebook, circa 1908 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - School Notebook with Exercises and Writings, 1914 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Writings, 1914, 1938, circa 1977, undated (Box 39, Folder 3-6)
  - Devotions Book, 1922 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Kate Gibson and Others, December 1927- April 1954 (Box 39, Folder 8-9, Box 40, Folder 1-5)
  - Diaries, January 1929-January 1948 (Box 40, Folder 6-8, Box 41, Folder 1-6)
  - Inscribed Bible, 1937 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Notepad -- Diary Entries and Expenses for Trip, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Mother Annie's Funeral Booklet, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Grace and William Knipe Obituaries, 1959, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Letters with Niece Kathe Burkhart, 1963-1989 (Box 42, Folder 5-7)
  - Scrapbook, 1975, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Photograph -- Knipe at 100 Years Old, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Notes -- Church Meetings, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks with Shorthand Notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
- Series VIII. Journals, Datebooks, and Diaries, 1966-2016; 9.75 Linear Feet in 19 and 1/2 manuscript boxes.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access is restricted to researchers until the donor is deceased.
  This series contains journals, notebooks, diaries, and datebooks dating from the 1960s to the 2010s. Burkhart's early notebooks from the 1960s to the 1980s contain her thoughts and feelings growing up in West Virginia as a teen and young adult navigating high school and college, and also include poetry, notes to boyfriends, as well as her thoughts on artworks, college class notes, and projects. Later writings were often kept in appointment books, and entries were frequently a mixture of personal and professional thoughts, including studio notes, project ideas, travel plans, finances, relationship issues, poetry, and personal goals. These books are presently not available to researchers.
  - Journals and Diaries, 1966, 1971-1972 (Box 47, Folder 1-9)
  - Journals and Diaries, 1972-1977 (Box 48, Folder 1-9)
  - Journals and Diaries, 1977-1980 (Box 49, Folder 1-8)
  - Journals and Diaries, 1980-1983 (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
  - Journals and Diaries, 1983-1985 (Box 51, Folder 1-6)
  - Journals and Diaries, August 1985-April 1989 (Box 52, Folder 1-6)
  - Journals and Diaries, May 1989-January 1991 (Box 53, Folder 1-6)
  - Journals and Diaries, February 1991-March 1993 (Box 54, Folder 1-5)
  - Journals and Diaries, April 1994-1996 (Box 55, Folder 1-5)
  - Journals and Diaries, September 1996-June 1999 (Box 56, Folder 1-5)
  - Journals and Diaries, June 1999-May 2003 (Box 57, Folder 1-6)
  - Journals and Diaries, July 2003-April 2007 (Box 58, Folder 1-5)
  - Journals and Diaries, 2006-2010 (Box 59, Folder 1-7)
  - Journals and Diaries, 2008-2011 (Box 60, Folder 1-9)
  - Journals and Diaries, December 2011-February 2014 (Box 61, Folder 1-6)
  - Journals and Diaries, 2013-undated (Box 62, Folder 1-6)
  - Appointment Books, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Books, 1987-1991 (Box 63, Folder 1-4)
  - Appointment Books, 1992-1997 (Box 64, Folder 1-5)
  - Appointment Books, 1998-2010 (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
  - Appointment Books, 2010, 2012, 2015-2016 (Box 66, Folder 1-2)